Link to the codepen: 
https://codepen.io/Isaiahflax/pen/rNNYxro



The Questions and Answers

1. What is Semantic HTML? 
“Semantic HTML” refers to the idea that all your HTML markup should convey the underlying meaning of your content—not its appearance. https://internetingishard.com/html-and-css/semantic-html/
   
 2. What is HTML used for? 
First developed by Tim Berners-Lee in 1990, HTML is short for Hypertext Markup Language. HTML is used to create electronic documents (called pages) that are displayed on the World Wide Web. Each page contains a series of connections to other pages called hyperlinks. https://www.computerhope.com › jargon › html
    
3. What is an attribute and where do we put it? 
An attribute is used to define the characteristics of an HTML element and is placed inside the element's opening tag. All attributes are made up of two parts − a name and a value

The name is the property you want to set. For example, the paragraph <p> element in the example carries an attribute whose name is align, which you can use to indicate the alignment of paragraph on the page.

The value is what you want the value of the property to be set and always put within quotations. The below example shows three possible values of align attribute: left, center and right. https://www.tutorialspoint.com/html/html_attributes.htm
   
 4. What is the h1 tag used for? How many times should I use it on a page?
The h1 is an HTML tag that indicates a heading on a website. Your h1 should describe the topic of your page. Some SEOs may be comfortable using multiple H1s, but in my experience, the one page/one H1 rule has given me the best SEO results. https://neilpatel.com/blog/h1-tag/
    
5. Name two tags that have required attributes
Anchor tags, <a>,  require a link, an href, and hypertext reference. Imgae tags, <img>, require a source, src.
    
6. What do we put in the head of our HTML document? 
The <head> element can include a title for the document, scripts, styles, meta information, and more.

The following elements can go inside the <head> element:

<title> (this element is required in an HTML document)
<style>
<base>
<link>
<meta>
<script>
<noscript> https://www.w3schools.com/tags/tag_head.asp
    
7. What is an id? 
The id attribute specifies a unique id for an HTML element (the value must be unique within the HTML document). The id attribute is most used to point to a style in a style sheet, and by JavaScript (via the HTML DOM) to manipulate the element with the specific id. https://www.w3schools.com › tags › att_id
  
  8. What elements can I add an id to? 
In HTML5, the id attribute can be used on any HTML element (it will validate on any HTML element. However, it is not necessarily useful).

In HTML 4.01, the id attribute cannot be used with: <base>, <head>, <html>, <meta>, <param>, <script>, <style>, and <title>. https://www.w3schools.com/tags/att_global_id.asp
   
 9. How many times can I use the same id on a page? 
Once
   
 10. What is a class? 
The HTML class attribute is used to define equal styles for elements with the same class name.

So, all HTML elements with the same class attribute will get the same style. https://www.w3schools.com/html/html_classes.asp
    
11. What elements can I add a class to? 
In HTML5, the class attribute can be used on any HTML element (it will validate on any HTML element. However, it is not necessarily useful).

In HTML 4.01, the class attribute cannot be used with: <base>, <head>, <html>, <meta>, <param>, <script>, <style>, and <title>.https://www.w3schools.com/tags/att_global_class.asp
    
12. How many times can I use the same class on a page? 
You can use the same class for all the elements if you want
   
 13. How do I get my link to open in a new tab?
The short answer is: just add a target="_blank" attribute to your links (anchor tags). https://www.thesitewizard.com/html-tutorial/open-links-in-new-window-or-tab.shtml
   
 14. What is the alt attribute used for? 
The required alt attribute specifies an alternate text for an image, if the image cannot be displayed. The alt attribute provides alternative information for an image if a user for some reason cannot view it (because of slow connection, an error in the src attribute, or if the user uses a screen reader
   
 15. How do I reference an id? 
#
    
16. What is the difference between a section and a div? 
<section>
The <section> element represents a generic section of a document or application. A section, in this context, is a thematic grouping of content. Each section should be identified, typically by including a heading (h1-h6 element) as a child of the <section> element.

Examples of sections would be chapters, the various tabbed pages in a tabbed dialog box, or the numbered sections of a thesis. A Web site’s home page could be split into sections for an introduction, news items, and contact information.

...

The <section> element is not a generic container element. When an element is needed only for styling purposes or as a convenience for scripting, authors are encouraged to use the <div> element instead. A general rule is that the <section> element is appropriate only if the element’s contents would be listed explicitly in the document’s outline.

(https://www.w3.org/TR/html/sections.html#the-section-element)

<div>
The <div> element has no special meaning at all. It represents its children. It can be used with the class, lang, and title attributes to mark up semantics common to a group of consecutive elements.

Note: Authors are strongly encouraged to view the <div> element as an element of last resort, for when no other element is suitable. Use of more appropriate elements instead of the <div> element leads to better accessibility for readers and easier maintainability for authors.

(https://www.w3.org/TR/html/grouping-content.html#the-div-element)
    
17. What is CSS used for?
 To describe how HTML elements are presented
    
18. How to we select an element? Example - every h2 on the page?
In a css file use .h2
   
 19. What is the difference between a class and an id? - Give me an example of when I might use each one.
id is more specific than class.
#ID's have special browser functionality
Classes have no special abilities in the browser, but ID's do have one very important trick up their sleeve. This is the "hash value" in the URL. If you have a URL like http://yourdomain.com#comments, the browser will attempt to locate the element with an ID of "comments" and will automatically scroll the page to show that element. It is important to note here that the browser will scroll whatever element it needs to in order to show that element, so if you did something special like a scrollable DIV area within your regular body, that div will be scrolled too.

This is an important reason right here why having ID's be absolutely unique is important. So your browser knows where to scroll!
#CSS doesn't care
Regarding CSS, there is nothing you can do with an ID that you can't do with a Class and vise versa. I remember when I was first learning CSS and I was having a problem, sometimes I would try and troubleshoot by switching around these values. Nope. CSS doesn't care.

#Javascript cares
JavaScript people are already probably more in tune with the differences between classes and ID's. JavaScript depends on there being only one page element with any particular id, or else the commonly used getElementById function wouldn't be dependable. For those familiar with jQuery, you know how easy it is to add and remove classes to page elements. It is a native and built in function of jQuery. Notice how no such function exists for ID's. It is not the responsibility of JavaScript to manipulate these values, it would cause more problems than it would be worth.
https://css-tricks.com/the-difference-between-id-and-class/

    20. How do we select classes in CSS?
.class
    
21. How do we select a p element with a single class of “human””?
p.human {}
    
22. What is a parent child selector? When would this be useful? The ("parent > child") selector selects all elements that are a direct child of the specified element.
Maybe you want to make the outer-most list items large and header-like, but the nested lists smaller and more body-copy like. Using a child combinator you can select only those top level list items and not worry about the large/header styling cascading down to the nested lists and having to fight against that styling. https://css-tricks.com/child-and-sibling-selectors/
  
  23. How do you select all links within a div with the class of sidebar?
div.sidebar{}
   
 24. What is a pseudo selector?
A CSS pseudo-class is a keyword added to a selector that specifies a special state of the selected element(s). For example, :hover can be used to change a button's color when the user's pointer hovers over it. https://developer.mozilla.org › docs › Web › CSS › Pseudo-classes
   
 25. What do we use the change the spacing between lines?
.class{
line-height: appropriate-height;
}
  
  26. What do we use to change the spacing between letters?
element{
letter-spacing: 0;
}
   
 27. What do we use to to change everything to CAPITALS? lowercase? Capitalize?
p {
    text-transform: lowercase;
    line-height: 3;
}

p::first-letter {
    text-transform: uppercase;
}
    
28. How do I add a 1px border around my div that is dotted and black?
div {
border-style: dotted;
border-width: 1px;
border-color: black;
}
   
 29. How do I select everything on the page? 
*{

}
   
 30. How do I write a comment in CSS?
/*this is a comment in CSS*/
   
31. How do I find out what file I am in, when I am using the command line? 
Type the command pwd
pwd means print working directory
  
32. Using the command line - how do I see a list of files/folders in my current folder?
ls
   
33. How do I remove a file via the command line? Why do I have to be careful with this? 
rm file-to-delete.file
Be careful because the file doesn't go to a trash folder it just gets deleted for ever.
    
34. Why should I use version control? 
Version control allows different people to work on the same project at the same time.
    
35. How often should I commit to github?
Everytime you want to save your changes to the project. To track changes over time.
    
36. What is the command we would use to push our repo up to github? 
git push
    
37. Walk me through Lambda's git flow. 
Step 1: Create my own version of the repo by forking the project.
Step 2: Add the TL as a collaborator 
Step 3: Clone the repo
Step 4: Make a branch on the fork named 'Isaiah-Flax'
git checkout -b 'Isaiah-Flax'
Run git branch to make sure it was commited properly.
Step 5: submit a pull request
use my fork as a base-fork
Add my TL as a reviewer on the project
Step 6: Accept the changes



Stretch Questions

    1. What is the difference between an inline element and a block element?
Basically, an inline element does not cause a line break (start on a new line) and does not take up the full width of a page, only the space bounded by its opening and closing tag. It is usually used within other HTML elements.
A block-level element always starts on a new line and takes up the full width of a page, from left to right. A block-level element can take up one line or multiple lines and has a line break before and after the element.https://codeburst.io/block-level-and-inline-elements-the-difference-between-div-and-span-2f8502c1f95b
   
 2. What happens when an element is positioned absolutely? 
An element with position: absolute; is positioned relative to the nearest positioned ancestor 
    
3. How do I make an element take up only the amount of space it needs but also have the ability to give it a width? 
   
 4. Name 3 elements that are diplay block by default, 2 elements that are display inline by default and 1 element that is display inline-block by default
   
 5. In your own words, explain the box model. What is the fix for the box model? 



   --> 